

Mobile Software Engineer (iOS Developer)

Personal Information

Location: United Kingdom, London Nationality: Iran

Place of Birth: Iran, Tehran Date of Birth: 1990/September/17

Contact Information

Phone: +44-7377178277 Email: <u>novinfard@gmail.com</u> Website: <u>www.novinfard.com</u>

Profile

I worked at Nini Magazine (NiniPlus) as a senior iOS developer and software project manager for last 3 years. We created a new app for the community of pregnant women where I built its iOS application, the real-time architecture of the software, associated web application backends, monitoring services and the RESTful and socket-based API. Moreover, I did some tasks in IT human resource management there.

On the other hand, backend development of mobile applications is one of my forte due to the fact that I have worked and developed web applications with some PHP frameworks like Codelgniter, MySQL and mongoDB for more than 5 years.

Academic Background

QUEEN MARY UNIVERSITY OF LONDON - 2017-2019

Master's degree, Software Engineering with Industrial Experience

SHARIF UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY – 2013-2015

Master's degree, Computer Systems Networking and Telecommunications

Main Skills

Mobile Applications, Objective-C, Swift, Backend Development, Web-socket, RESTful WebServices,, CoreData, Realm

Other Skills

Project Management, Real-time applications, Web Applications, PHP, MySQL, MongoDB, Codelgniter, Joomla!, XHTML, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Scrum, Source Control, Git

Publications

M.R.Shahmoradi, S.Novinfard, "Developing a web service to automatic mapping web pages to mobile devices" 15th Iranian students conference on electrical engineering (ISCEE2012), August 2012

Academic Awards

Organiser at 17th Iranian students conference on electrical engineering (ISCEE2014), December 2014

Best Panel Chairman at 16th Iranian students conference on electrical engineering (ISCEE2013), September 2013

Certificates

WEB DEVELOPING ENGINEER WITH JAVASCRIPT

Technical and Vocational education organiser of IRAN MARCH 2010, GRADE 74 FROM 100, 304 HOURS

Work Experience

MOBILE SOFTWARE ENGINEER (IOS DEVELOPER) AT NINI MAGAZINE; TEHRAN, IRAN

AUGUST 2014 - AUGUST 2017

Niniplus mobile application March 2014 - August 2017

Social network and real-time messaging for the community of pregnant women

Niniplus SMS web application August 2014 - March 2014

This application is an interactive SMS system which provides weekly messaging for pregnant women

FOUNDER & LEAD WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPER AT EGOLT; TEHRAN, IRAN

MARCH 2012 - JUNE 2017

Transcription Helper iOS application September 2016 - present

The Transcribe Helper application is an assistant for people who want to work out a piece of audio, in order to write it out.

Egolt Archive Joomla! extension April 2013 - June 2017

SENIOR WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPER AT IRIB; ZANJAN, IRAN

FEBRUARY 2009 - MARCH 2013 (4 YEARS, 2 MONTHS)

MANAGER & SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER AT ANDIA WEBGOSTER; ZANJAN, IRAN

OCTOBER 2009 - OCTOBER 2011 (2 YEARS, 1 MONTH)

Negah Media web applicationSeptember 2009 - January 2011Kerman / Semnan / Hamadan IRIB websiteSeptember 2011 - May 2012

Languages

ENGLISH PROFESSIONAL WORKING PROFICIENCY

IELTS Academic Module Certificate with band score 7.0 (20th April 2017)

PERSIAN NATIVE

Interests and hobbies

Fitness, Playing Chess, Watching movies, Playing Piano, Help programmers